An Annotated Calendar of the Letters of Charles Darwin in the Library of the American Philosophical Society 1799-1882 Mss.B.D25
American Philosophical Society
- Calendar of Letters
  - To [Philip Lutley] SCLATER; Down Bromley/ Kent. (handwritten), [1866] Dec 24 [end. Dec 1866]; 324; LS; 7 3/4 x5; 1p. and end. [9402/ C Darwin/ Enclosure/ Dec 1866] and 2p. enclosure
    1. Jacob W. Velie was Curator of the Chicago Academy of Sciences from 1879 to 1893; see A. T. Andreas, History of Chicago from the Earliest Period to the Present Time, 3v. (Chicago: A. T. Andreas Co., 1884-86), III, 430-31. Suzanne W. Brown, Secretary to the Director, Chicago Academy of Sciences, provided this information.
  - To [George Henry Kendrick] THWAITES; Down Bromley Kent (handwritten), [?1867] Jan 31.; 325; LS; 8.25 x5.5 2p. (enclosures wanting)
    J[ames] Emerson Tennant [ sic; Tennent] says captured elephants weep when moaning and screaming; observe this, and see if the "orbicularis palpebrarum" acts to wrinkle the surrounding skin and partially or wholly close the eyes; encloses "some printed copies of my queries on expression, with two of the more important ones a little amended"; would appreciate "a few observations on any race". 1
    1. On the subjects discussed in this letter, see: Darwin, Expression of the Emotions (1872), 21, 167-68, and 167n; and R. B. Freeman and P. J. Gautrey, "Charles Darwin's Queries about Expression," Bull. Br. Mus. nat. Hist. (hist. Ser.), 4 (1972): 205-19.
  - To J[ames] P[hilip] Mansel WEALE; Down (type 4), [1867] Feb 22. [pmk. FE 22/ 67]; 326; LS; 8 x5; 4p. and env., add. [J. P. Mansel Weale Esq/ Bedford/ Algoa Bay/ Cape Colony], end. [Feb: 1867 in answer to a/ letter from Bedford]
    Thanks for letter and paper on Bonatea, 1 which CD read and forwarded to Linnean Society; several points in it are new to CD; as it has published on orchids before and is in arrears, the Society may not publish the paper, but it is a valuable paper nonetheless; Weale's observations on Asclepias are new and curious; Robert Brown said years ago that he did not understand how pollen masses were retained by stigmas which do not emit viscid matter; has not heard of Brown's conduct as botanist in Weale's colony; thanks for praise of CD's work; "It is a most serious drawback to me that I am very seldom able to go to London or to see any of my fellow-workers in Natural History owing to my constant state of ill-health".
    1. Weale, "Notes on the Structure and Fertilization of the Genus Bonates, with a Special Description of a Species Found at Bedford, South Africa," J. Linn. Soc. (Bot.), 10 (1869): 470-76.
  - To [John Maurice] HERBERT; Down (type 4), [1867]; 327; LS; 8 x5; 3p.
    Thanks for letter; knew [Richard] Dawes as an undergraduate, but had seen him only once since; will send two guineas for his memorial; remembers that [Marmaduke] Ramsay of Jesus [College, Cambridge] told Dawes he would do nothing but laugh through life, and all agreed, which shows "how little a man some times knows himself"; is "much better" in health after "two or three bad years", but [John] Tyndall gives "too flourishing an account", as CD is "never well for the whole day"; declines invitation; invites the Herberts to Down House.
    1. Dawes died on March 10, 1867.
  - To [Charles] LYELL; Down (type 4), [1867] June 1st; 328; ALS; 8 x5; 4p. (enclosure wanting)
    Printed, with minor changes: Life and Letters III, 65-66. At beginning of letter is: does not think H[enry] Parker ever reviewed the Origin; perhaps Lyell refers to an article 1 on [George Douglas Campbell,] D[uke] of Argyll, which CD praised and a copy of which CD encloses; please return it.
    1. Probably "The Reign of Law," Saturday Review, 23 (1867): 82-84. But see also: Saturday Review for November 15, 1862; and Life and Letters III, 274.
  - To [Charles] LYELL; Down (type 4), [1867] June 9th; 329; ALS; 8 x5; 3p.
    The "variability & passage of Primrose into Cowslip must be given up", since CD has just proved that common oxlip is "a natural Hybrid between the two", but "Bardfield oxlip, which occurs almost only in Essex (the P. Elatior of Jacquin) is a perfectly distinct & good & third species"; is glad Lyell likes H[enry] Parker's article; 1 wants to discuss N[orth] British Review and to see the Lyells; should go to London on fifteenth and, "stomacho volente", will breakfast with Lyell on Monday the seventeenth; 2 Lyell's note about Primula lacked enclosure.
    2. CD was in London June 17-24, 1867; see "Darwin's Journal," 17.
  - To [Charles] KINGSLEY; Down (type 4), [1867]; 330; LS; 8 x5; 9p. (incomplete) (enclosures wanting)
    Thanks for deeply interesting letter; lends paper by Cap[tain Frederick Wollaston] Hutton, "a very acute observer", from a collection of reviews of Darwin, Origin (1859+); 2 has just finished [George Douglas Campbell,] Duke [of Argyll]'s book [ The Reign of Law (London: Alexander Strahan, 1867)] and [Fleeming Jenkins, "The Origin of Species,"] N. Br. Rev., [ 46 (1867); 149-71 (issued June, 1867)]; Duke's book "very well written, very interesting, honest & clever & very arrogant. How cooly [sic] he says that even J[ohn] S[tuart] Mill does not know what he means"; parts of book are weak, such as about rudimentary organs and structure of humming birds; criticizes Duke's argument regarding diversity of structure; see CD's comments on this in Darwin, Origin (1866), 226, and on beauty, p. 238; sends copy of Origin to Kingsley; see also enclosed letter by [Alfred Russel] Wallace; Duke speaks absurdly of beauty "existing independently of any sentient being to appreciate it"; thinks deity should not come into scientific discussion; glad Kingsley admits sexual selection, which CD has studied recently; on lack of beauty in female birds, Wallace finds relation between nature of nest and female's beauty; 3 female peacock merely selects beauty, not every detail of color, so circular spot could become circular zone; "correlation of growth" is bad term, now prefers "correlation of variation"; Duke's attack on this is unfair; Duke wrong about natural selection; "I presume he wd not deny that [Robert] Bakewell, Collins, &c had in one sense made our improved breeds of cattle, yet of course the initial variations have naturally arisen; but until selected, they remained unimportant, & in this same sense natural selection seems to me all-important"; N. Br. Rev. is telling and hostile, but lacking in knowledge; reviewer wrong that domestic races formed rapidly; regarding antiquity of world, "I cannot implicitly believe the mathematicians, seeing what widely different results [Samuel] Haughton [, William] Hopkins & [William] Thompson [ sic; Thomson, Lord Kelvin] have arrived at"; 4 note from [Charles] Lyell, just received, dismisses N. Br. Rev.; study of geological work done during glacial period impresses one with necessary lapse of time; who wrote N. Br. Rev.?
    1. CD read the Duke's book during this year; see Life and Letters III, 65.
    2. CD probably refers to Hutton's review of the Origin in the Geologist (1861): 132-36 and 183-88. See Life and Letters II, 362; More Letters, II, 183-84; and Vorzimmer, Reprint Catalogue, item R.79.
    3. See More Letters, I, 283 (letter 203); ibid., II, 59-61 (letter 429); and ibid., II, 72-74 (letter 440).
    4. See Joe D. Burchfield, "Darwin and the Dilemma of Geological Time," Isis, 65 (1974): 301-21; and idem, Lord Kelvin and the Age of the Earth (New York: Science History Publications, 1975).
  - To [Charles] LYELL; Down (type 4), [1867] July 18; 331; LS; 8 x5; 6p. and sketch
    First portion printed, with minor changes: Life and Letters III, 71-72. At end of this portion is: thanks about six-fingered men, but that chapter [i.e. chapter 12 of Darwin, Variation under Domestication (1868)] is finished.
    Next portion printed, with minor changes: More Letters, II, 141-43 (letter 493). At end of letter is: [Ludwig] Rütimeyer sent his book [ Über die Herkunft Unserer Thierwelt: Eine Zoogeographische Skizza... (Basel: H. Georg, 1867)], but has not read it or cut pages; wishes Lyell good progress in book [ The Principles of Geology, 10th ed., 2v. (London: John Murray, 1866-1868), volume 2].
  - To [Charles] LYELL; Down (type 4), [1867] Aug 22; 332; LS (postscript in CD's hand); 8 x5; 4p.
    Printed, with minor changes and minor omissions: Life and Letters III, 72-73. p. 73, line 2, missing phrase is "with all its bad judgment & taste". At end of letter is: regards to wife [Mary Elizabeth Horner Lyell]. At beginning of postscript is: leave French edition [of Darwin, Origin ( Freeman 420) (1866)] at 6 Queen Anne St. [home of CD's brother, Erasmus Alvey Darwin]. p. 73, line 2 of postscript, change "Russian has" to "Russian, Kowelowsky [i.e. Valdimir Onufrievich Kovalevsky], has".
  - To [?Cassell, Petter, & Galpin, publishers] 1; Down (type 4), [1867] Aug 24 [end. 24th. August 1867]; 333; LS; 8 x5; 3p. and end. [923/ C. Darwin/ 24th. August 1867]
    Has had much correspondence with [Vladimir Onufrievich] Kovalevsky, who has visited Down House; he is brother of "distinguished naturalist" [Aleksandr Onufrievich Kovalevsky]; he is preparing a translation of Darwin, [ Variation under Domestication (1868)], 2 and has translated some expensive German works; he has made liberal offers to CD for translation; trusts Kovalevsky, but cannot answer for his "pecuniary circumstances", which are probably good.
    1. This correspondent was suggested in a private correspondence to the author from Professor James A. Rogers, Department of History, Claremont Men's College.
    2. For citation of this translation in Russian, which is impossible to reproduce here, see B. Mus. Catalogue, 48, 964, second entry from top.
  - To [Charles] LYELL; Down (type 4), [1867] Oct 4; 334; ALS (portion not in CD's hand); 8 x5; 4p.
    Printed in full, with minor changes: More Letters, I, 299-300 (letter 217).
  - To [George Henry Kendrick] THWAITES; Down (type 2), [1867] Oct 26; 335; LS; 5.5 x4.5 1p. and enc. 1
    Since corr. has helped CD with queries, encloses a few slightly corrected copies; stir up any likely and accurate man.
    1. Enclosure is one-page broadside, Queries about Expression, identical to that identified as version number 2 in Richard Broke Freeman and Peter Jack Gautrey, "Charles Darwin's Queries about Expression," Bull. Br. Mus. nat. Hist. (hist. Ser.), 4 (1972): 207ff.
  - To [Charles] LYELL; Down (type 4), [1867] Oct 31st; 336; LS (postscript in CD's hand); 8 x5; 4p.
    Printed, with minor changes and minor omissions: More Letters, II, 4-5 (letter 381). At beginning of letter is: Emma [Wedgwood Darwin] has headache. p. 4, line 10, change "distances" to "differences [ sic]". At end of letter is: brother [Erasmus Alvey Darwin] is home now.
  - To [Charles] LYELL; Down (type 4), [1867] Dec 7; 337; LS; 8 x5; 3p.
    Printed in full: More Letters, I, 284-85 (letter 205).
  - To [Philip Lutley] SCLATER; Down (type 4), [1867] Decr. 9th [end. Dec 1867]; 338; ALS; 8 x5; 2p. and end. [10392/ C. Darwin/ abt. Index &c/ Dec 1867]
    Wants both indices, since has no index of Proc. zool. Soc. Lond.; send to same address as "Journal &c"; wants more recent list of fellows than 1858 version which CD has at present; December number of Intellectual Observer does not contain article by Sclater; supposes article on barbets is in November number; 1 enjoys talk with Sclater.
    1. Supposition is correct. See Sclater, "Barbets, and Their Distribution," Intellectual Observer, 12 (1867-1868): 241-46. Talk with Sclater probably occurred while CD was in London in late November and early December; see "Darwin's Journal," 17.
  - To [Albert Charles Lewis Gotthilf GÜNTHER]; Down (type 4), [?1867]; 339; ALS; 8 x5; 1p., end. [to A Günther 1870]
    Thanks for note; information is just what CD wanted; has looked at plates and text; cases are "capital & quite new to me"; should have known that corr.'s work would have this in it. 2
    1. Apparently, this letter is a reply to a letter from Günther dated 19 December 1867. This letter is bound in volume 82 of the Darwin Papers at University Library, Cambridge. See Handlist of Darwin Papers, 21.
    2. CD probably refers to Günther, Catalogue of the Fishes in the Collection of the British Museum, 8v. (London: 1859-1870).
  - To [?Julius Victor CARUS] 1; no location, [?1867]; 340; ALS (incomplete); 10.5 x8; 1p.
    Gives definitions of the following terms: shoulder-pad; cross and intercross; structure; constitution. Shows differences in the terms "constitution", "habit", and "instinct". Is astonished and pleased that translation 1 will be ready by May.
    1. The translation is probably the first German edition of Darwin, Variation under Domestication [ Freeman 459] (1868). This information, the year for this letter, and the recipient were suggested by Sydney Smith, St. Catharine's College, Cambridge University.
  - To [George Henry Kendrick] THWAITES; Down (type 4), [?1867-1868]; 341; ALS; 8 x5; 3p.
    Printed, with minor changes and minor omissions: More Letters, II, 90-91 (letter 455).
    1. See: Darwin to Thwaites, Jan. 31, [?1867], above; "Darwin's Journal," 17-18; and Darwin, Descent of Man (1871), II, 284ff and 319.
  - To [George Henry Kendrick] THWAITES; Down (type 4), [?1867-1868]; 342; ALS; 8 x5; 4p.
    Thanks for note of April 1; case of monkeys is hopeless; take no more trouble about human expression; learned after writing that orbicularis palpebrarum contracts on trumpeting elephants in Zoological Gardens, and distress brings tears; would appreciate further details; [Edgar Leopold] Layard says a breed of fowls in Ceylon has hen alone colored like sooty white plumage; are young of breed sooty like hen or pure white like cock?
    1. For further discussion of points in this letter, see the following letters above: Darwin to Thwaites, Jan. 31, [?1867]; ibid., Oct. 26, [1867]; and ibid., Feb. 13, [?1867-1868]. See also Darwin, Variation under Domestication (1868), I, 256 and 256n.
  - To [George Henry Kendrick] THWAITES; Down (type 4), [?1867-1868]; 343; ALS; 8 x5; 2p.
    Thanks to Thwaites and to [Edgar Leopold] Layard for trouble; is surprised at result, since Layard is trustworthy and [Edward] Blyth says same about fowls in Bengal; do not send fowls, since Zoological Society foolishly objects to domestic varieties.
  - To [John Maurice HERBERT]; Down (type 4), [1868]; 344; LS; 8 x5; 3p.
    Thanks for congratulations [because son George Howard Darwin was second wrangler at Cambridge]; son has pleased CD; reminds CD of celebration of [Charles Thomas] Whitley's wrangler honors and honors of corr.; old microscope, received anonymously [from Herbert], reminds CD of their old friendship; regards to wife.
    1. See Emma Darwin, II, 216-17. This letter is part of the Herbert collection.
  - To [Philip Lutley] SCLATER; Down (type 4), [1868] Feb. 28 [end. March 1868]; 345; ALS; 8 x5; 1p. and end. [200/ C. Darwin/ to Secretary/ March 1868]
    Thinks Capt. [Philip Parker] King's birds [?collected on 1826-1830 voyage of H.M.S. Adventure] were given first to Zoological Society and then to British Museum, but habitats for many specimens are incorrectly marked.
  - To [Charles] LYELL; 6 Queen Anne St., [1868 (?March 3-10)]; 346; ALS; 8 x5; 4p.
    Thanks for long letter, somewhat consoling, "but I take [the argument for a short age of the earth based on a calculation of the combustion rate of] the Sun much to heart"; is consoled by argument based on ignorance of universe and of process causing incandescence in heavenly bodies; formed opinion that continents have had long endurance on basis of facts of geographical distribution; see Darwin, Origin [(1959), chap. 11, esp. 357-58] and Darwin, Coral Reefs; agrees about denudation, had concluded that matter brought to lower level was much ground up; this would not affect "Scotch streams"; is tired from morning in British Museum.
    1. Year is penciled on letter by CD's son. During 1868, CD was at 6 Queen Anne Street only during March 3-10 and November 7-16; see "Darwin's Journal," 17-18. March period is preferred because of date on which William Thomson, Lord Kelvin, read his famous paper on the age of the earth; see Thomson, "On Geological Time," [read February 27, 1868], Trans. geol. Soc. Glasg., 3 (1871): 1-28.
  - To [? Thomas RIVERS]; Down (type 4), [?1868] Mar 4; 347; LS; 8 x5; 3p.
    Thanks for note with details on Le Compte family and on moss roses [ Rosa centifolia]; regrets having missed recent papers by corr. on inheritance, "but from living in the country & not seeing periodicals I have no doubt missed much of importance"; hopes CD has acknowledged corr. adequately.
  - To J[ohn] Jenner WEIR; 6 Queen Street/ Cavendish Sqe/ W., [1868 ca. March 6] [end. March/ 1868; pmk. MR6/ 68; wmk. 1860]; 348; ALS; 8 x5; 7p. and env., add. [J. Jenner Weir/ 6. Haddo Villas/ Black-heath/ S.E.], end. [Darwin/ March/ 1868]
    Printed in full, with minor changes: More Letters, II, 66-68 (letter 435).
  - To [Charles] LYELL; 4 Chester Place/ N.W, [1868 March 19]; 349; ALS; 8 x5; 3p.
    Thanks for "the grand Book [i.e. Lyell, Principles of Geology, 10th ed., 2v. (London: John Murray, 1866-1868), volume 2]"; has read only the newspaper since coming to London [on March 3], and vowed not to look at Lyell's book, but curiosity forced him to read some of the organic part; Lyell has given a "fair history of the progress of opinion on Species; but you will perhaps think it would be strange if I did not say so, seeing what high credit you give to me"; is delighted that Lyell alludes to pangenesis; "an untried hypothesis is always dangerous ground"; "My fear has always been that Pangenesis would be a still-born infant, over whom no one would rejoice or cry"; is eager to read chapters on domestication and on man.
    1. Full date written on first page in pencil.
  - To D. PENNETHORNE; Down (type 4), [1868] May 22nd. [pmk. MY 23/ 68]; 350; LS; 8 x5; 2p. and env., add. [D. Pennethorne Esq/ 1 New Square/ Lincolns Inn/ London]
    Thanks for note and paper on man; 1 has studied the question for years and is writing essay on it, so found nothing new in corr.'s paper; agrees with corr. on "almost all points".
    1. See Vorzimmer, Reprint Catalogue, item Q. 131. CD's essay is probably his book, Descent of Man (1871).
  - To "Gentlemen" [?Bibliographisches Institute in Hildburghausen, Germany]; Down (type 4), 1868 June 8; 351; LS; 8 x5; 4p.
    Has suggested to [John] Murray the publication of an English edition of [Alfred Edmund] Brehm's [Illustrirtes] Thierleben [6v. (Hildburghausen: Bibliographisches Institute, 1864-1869)], but Murray thinks England saturated with [T.W.] Wood, [ ?Curiosities of Ornithology]; thinks Brehm's book is " quite excellent, & the illustrations are admirable"; wants to borrow stereotypes of some of Brehm's illustrations for Darwin, [ Descent of Man (1871)]; thinks this will further advertise Brehm's work; will pay for stereotypes; wants from volume 1, the three monkeys pp. 54, 57, and 119; from volume 3, bower bird p. 317, Paradisea p. 324, Cosmetornis p. 669, Rupicola p. 745, and Cephalopterus p. 752; from volume 4, hummingbird pp. 109 and 111, [Crepidonia?] p. 326, Polyplectron p. 471, Machetes p. 625, Palamedea p. 739, and Rhynchaea p. 743. 1
    1. For stereotypes used by CD, see Darwin, Descent of Man (1871), II, 42, 47, 59, 70, 75, 88, 90, 202, 283, 309, and 311. Publisher of Brehm's work was assumed to be recipient of this letter.
  - To [Charles] LYELL; Down (type 4), 1868 July 14; 352; LS; 8 x5; 4p.
    Printed, with minor changes: More Letters, II, 160-61 (letter 508). At beginning of letter is: thanks for [Constantin Wilhelm Lambert] Glöger [ sic; Gloger], [ ?Das Abandern der Vogel... (Breslau: 1833) 1], but already has it, so has sent it to Zoological Society; thanks also about hairy men, which CD possesses; [George Henry] Lewes has published three or four articles altogether, but not consecutively and more are yet to appear; 2 differs from Lewes on many points, but finds independent thinking on subject refreshing.
    1. See Darwin, Variation under Domestication (1868), II, 298.
    2. See Cat. scient. Pap., 3, 995; 8, 216; and 12, 445.
  - To [Thomas Campbell] EYTON; Down (type 4), [?1868] Aug. 25th; 353; ALS; 8 x5; 2p.
    Glad to see Eyton's handwriting; thanks for Eyton's Osteology [i.e. Osteologia Avium: A Sketch of the Osteology of Birds (Wellington: R. Hobson, 1867)]; congratulates Eyton on perseverance; had heard of Eyton's skeleton of Opisthocomus; sorry about Eyton's eyes; was too ill to have been at [B.A.A.S. mmeting at] Norwich [August 19-26, 1868]; remembers having hunted and fished at Eyton as a youth.
  - To [George Henry Kendrick] THWAITES; Down (type 4), 1868 Sep 2.; 354; LS; 8 x5; 2p.
    Thanks for "taking all my questions so very kindly"; Thwaites has entered on fowl question in earnest; thanks to [S. O.] Glenie for "excellent letter"; has written a letter of thanks in return. 1
    1. See Darwin, Expression of the Emotions (1872), 21, 167, and 252. See also letter from Darwin to Thwaites, May 19, [?1867-1868], above.
  - To?; Down (type 4), 1868 Sept. 25; 355; ALS; 8 x5; 1p.
    Has received specimen and forwarded it to [Joseph Dalton] Hooker; will write when he hears Hooker's verdict; congratulates corr. for zeal.
  - To Carl Ritter von SCHERZER; Down (type 4), 1868 Oct 25 [pmk. OC 25/ 68]; 356; LS; 8 x5; 2p. and env., add. [Ministerial Rath/ Dr Carl Ritter von Scherzer/ Alsergrund/ Liechtensteinstrasse/ Vienna/ via Belgium/ No 2.]
    Thanks for letter of October 20 and offer of aid; thanks for copy of the instructions; thanks for "translating & inserting the questions on expression"; 1 good wishes for voyage [to East Asia]. 2
    1. See Darwin, Expression of the Emotions (1872), 15-16.
    2. See Poggendorff, III, 1184.
  - To [William Darwin] FOX; Down (type 4), [1868] Dec. 12th; 357; ALS; 8 x5; 1p.
    Thanks for letter just received; will find Fox's return on the sheep and cattle very useful; 1 must prepare a new [fifth] edition of "that everlasting Origin"; 2 "I am sick of correcting."
    1. See Darwin, Descent of Man (1871), I, 304-05.
    2. This edition was prepared between December 26, 1868, and February 10, 1869; see "Darwin's Journal," 18. This is basis for determination of year for this letter.
  - To [George Henry Kendrick] THWAITES; Down (type 4), 1868 Dec 29.; 358; LS; 8 x5; 4p.
    Thanks to Thwaites and friends for taking trouble about fowls; results doubtful if not the pure breed; is "unwilling to believe that [Edward] Blyth & [Edgar Leopold] Layard were both mistaken"; do males of black chickens mentioned by Layard undergo change when they become adult; is glad to see [S. O.] Glenie's letter; thank Glenie and Layard; is astonished that Glenie saw no contraction of orbicular muscle in elephants, since CD and others have seen this plainly on elephants in Zoological Gardens; perhaps too great a contraction is expected; thanks for specimen showing surprising difference in form of leaves. 1
    1. See letter to Thwaites, September 2, 1868, above.
  - To [Thomas Campbell] EYTON; Down (type 4), 1869 Jan 24; 359; LS; 8 x5; 3p.
    Cannot provide needed information; glad Eyton continues to work on osteology of birds; has not seen Alph[onse] M[ilne] Edwards's book [probably Recherches Anatomiques et Paléontologiques pour Servir à l'Histoire des Oiseaux Fossiles de la France, 4v. (Paris: V. Masson et Fils, 1867-1871), II, published in 1868 or 1869], but hears it is excellent; how many months after birth do horns appear in males of fallow deer? 1
    1. See Darwin, Descent of Man (1871), I, 288n.
  - To [John] PHILLIPS; Down (type 4), 1869 Jan 27; 360; LS; 8 x5; 2p.
    Thanks for book on Vesuvius [ Vesuvius: A History of the Mountain and of Its Successive Eruptions (Oxford: 1869)], which has not yet arrived.